[MILVERTON]
Is that...?
If I recall correctly, his
name is William James Moriarty.
Second son of
the Moriarty family
and young mathematics prodigy.
Interesting.
So that is the man with
whom I am competing.
I see. I must thoroughly
investigate him at once
and add him to the list.
After all,
I, Charles Augustus Milverton,
am thorough in my work.
[WILLIAM]
Okay, so this time.
There is a certain number that
goes into both these boxes.
Do you know what it is?
Uhh...
It's impossible to have
12 of one thing
and 20 of something else
and for them to add up
the same number.
Perhaps I should have
started with an easier problem.
The correct answer's...
What? But that
doesn't make sense!
[WILLIAM] It does if
they're units of money.
[WILLIAM]
Twelve pence is one shilling.
Twenty shillings is one pound.
Which means that
one pound is 240 pence.
Now, let me see.
That would get you...
Right, 240 loaves of bread.
What?! We could eat like kings!
Really?!
[BOY 18A]
So if we had a hundred pounds...
[BOY 18B]
That'd be...
[BOY 18B, BOY 18A]
...24,000 loaves!
That's more than
I could eat in a lifetime!
[BOYS laugh]
[CHILDREN grunt]
[BOY 18B]
This is all we get again?
Here. You can have
mine if you'd like.
I'm not feeling
very hungry tonight.
[BOY 18B]
Thank you.
[chuckles]
[LOUIS]
Hm?
[sighs]
- -[footsteps]
- -[WILLIAM] Madam.
It's you two.
What brings you here
so late in the evening?
We thought there might be
something troubling you.
That perhaps someone had
swindled the orphanage
out of its funds.
[gasps]
[WILLIAM]
Are we wrong?
But how could you know that?
Similarly to the almshouse,
we're supported through
donations made by the nobility,
as I'm sure you're aware.
Last month,
an aristocrat by the name
of Lord Baxter visited me.
[BAXTER] I require a meager
amount, a mere 300 pounds,
and then construction on
the orphanage can begin.
The other day you received
a generous donation,
or so I've heard.
I'm begging you. Show mercy.
For the sake of the orphans,
may I please borrow the money?
I finally found the perfect plot
on which to build the orphanage.
But it'll be sold
to someone else
if I do not put
a deposit down at once.
But the children here...
Trust me! If something happens
that prevents me
from paying you back,
I offer myself in exchange.
[WOMAN 18A] The 300 wasn't
my own personal funds,
so I knew up front that it would
be wrong for me to lend it out.
But he gave me a
certificate of borrowing.
And I thought a nobleman's
word was absolute, so I...
However, the appointed
day came and went
and there was no sign
he would pay me back.
Or of the orphanage being built.
[WILLIAM]
If you wouldn't mind, madam,
I'd like to examine
the certificate.
[BAXTER]
Mmhm.
[gasps] You poor hungry waifs.
Here, buy some food.
[WILLIAM] We have no need
for your alms, Mister Baxter.
The fact is
we're here on behalf of
the madam from our orphanage.
I trust you know of
whom I'm speaking.
[BAXTER]
The madam,
is she feeling under
the weather, perhaps?
[LOUIS] Her hands are full
tending to the orphanage.
Poor woman.
I assume this
concerns the 300 pounds
I had borrowed
from her last we met.
Unfortunately,
construction of the
orphanage has not proceeded.
There's also the
matter of finding someone
to manage the project.
I'm afraid I'm out of my depth.
You're mistaken.
Huh?
[WILLIAM]
We're not here to inquire about
how construction is progressing.
Rather, we're here to collect
the money you borrowed,
if you'd kindly return it.
Beg your pardon,
but this coming month
I will be earning profit
through my trading.
Once this happens, I intend
to repay the money post haste.
[WILLIAM] While I appreciate
that, the truth is
we don't even have enough
to afford food at the moment.
If you do not repay
the money immediately,
our orphanage will
be unable to operate.
[BAXTER] The importance of
the money is not lost on me.
However, I cannot return
what I do not have.
[BAXTER grunts]
[WILLIAM]
I understand. In that case,
what if we were to assume
your debt with the madam
and put up the 300 pounds?
[BAXTER]
Uh.
- -[coins jingle]
- -[gasps]
[WILLIAM] As you can see,
we are good for it.
That's astonishing.
How did a child come
into such wealth?
[WILLIAM]
I've consulted with many adults
and saved what they've
rewarded me over time.
Furthermore,
after hearing of your
unfortunate circumstances...
[WILLIAM] ...it sounds as
though you could use more.
I will personally lend
you an additional 300.
I hope this will help avoid
future delays with construction.
[BAXTER gasps]
You're saying
you're prepared to
lend me 600 pounds
and my debt to the orphanage
will be written off?
We have a deal!
I accept your offer.
You name the conditions!
Will the same terms
as the contract
I had with the madam suffice?
Yes.
But I'll only accept the same
conditions, to the letter.
Your repayment date will be
on the first of next month.
[BAXTER]
All right, that settles it.
Let's take this to
the notary right away!
[LOUIS] Here is the 300
pounds we're lending you
after taking out the
amount owed to the madam.
That concludes our business.
Well, until the
first of next month.
I'm certain I'll be
able to repay you.
[WILLIAM]
I have no doubt.
If you'll excuse us,
we must see this money
gets delivered safely.
[BAXTER cackling]
[BAXTER] Once again, I have
enough to freely amuse myself.
The have-nots give
what little they possess
to the cultured elite--
that's the way of the world.
If you wish to curse something,
curse the situation
you've placed yourself in!
[coughs]
Brother, are you certain
it was a wise choice
to give that man
another 300 pounds?
Of course, I lent
it under the same
conditions as the
madam, after all.
Read the contract's
last provision.
[LOUIS grunts]
[LOUIS]
"On demand,
we promise to take a pound
of the borrower's flesh
if the bonder is unable
to pay a debt repayment
at the specified date."
Wh-Why, this contract,
it's similar to the one in...
That's right.
The agreement Shylock
and Antonio entered into
from the classic work,
William Shakespeare's
The Merchant of Venice  .
Apparently, he's
a lover of the arts.
[LOUIS]
However, in the play,
the court does not allow
Shylock to cut out his flesh.
Nor does he even get the
money he lent returned to him.
[WILLIAM] True, but our
ending will be different.
[LOUIS grunts]
We'll use his avarice
to our advantage...
...in the most famous court
case the world's ever heard.
This court will now begin legal
proceedings into the matter
of the default on the loan
agreement arranged by
the plaintiff and entered
into by the defendant.
Furthermore, the trial
will be on the record
in accordance with statute.
False testimony is a punishable
offence in this court,
so make sure to choose
your words carefully.
Both parties, are you ready?
[JUDGE 18A]
I couldn't believe my own eyes
when I read the complaint.
But sure enough,
he is just a child.
We'll begin.
We'll start with an opening
statement from the plaintiff.
[WILLIAM]
Yes, my lord.
As stated in my complaint,
I, the plaintiff, am seeking
immediate repayment for
the 600 pounds I lent
as designated in the bond and
agreed to by the defendant.
Very well.
The defendant may now
make his statement.
In regard to my
client, Lord Baxter,
the man has zero current assets
that can be used to
pay off this debt,
as seen in the
submitted documents.
I think it's evident this sum
cannot immediately be paid
as demanded by the plaintiff.
My lord, begging your pardon,
I would like to question the
defendant's financial situation
with permission?
[JUDGE 18A]
Granted.
Per these records,
you currently do not
possess any asset holdings.
Yet, Mister Baxter,
you reside in a high-class
residential area.
Had it not occurred to you
to sell your lavish estate?
[BAXTER] As much as I'd
like to, I cannot do that.
Your reasons being?
I'm actually
borrowing that estate
from a rather good
friend of mine.
I couldn't sell it
if I wanted to.
I see. We shall move on then.
You also operate a trading
company, do you not?
If you were to sell off
the ship owned by the company,
or even the company itself,
would repayment not be possible?
[BAXTER] I'm afraid
I cannot do that, either.
Whilst the trading
company does exist,
it's only on paper;
there are no buildings.
And the freighter
I had pinned all hopes
of seeing us through
became shipwrecked.
It won't be returning to port.
We are insured and the company's
losses will be covered,
but speaking practically,
the venture's bankrupt.
Like the estate,
it was not included with all
your documented assets
because it has no real value.
[BAXTER]
Yes, that is correct.
It's truly a pathetic tale.
I have my title
but little else to show.
Nothing but a fallen aristocrat,
without a single
possession to my own name!
Indeed. It seems that
repayment is impossible.
What would you like to do?
Seems I have no other option
but to give up on being repaid.
[BAXTER chuckles]
[WILLIAM]
As such...
[gasps]
[WILLIAM]
...in accordance with the
other provision of the contract,
I will extract
one pound of flesh
from the body of the
defendant as repayment.
[JUDGE 18A]
Now, wait.
You're not seriously
requesting a pound of flesh?
I am, as is my legal right
stated in this contract
officially issued by
a notary solicitor.
If the terms of the
agreement are not recognized,
the entire nation's sovereignty
must be called into question.
[JUDGE 18A]
It is true, contractually,
the request must be
recognized by the court.
[LAWYER 18A, BAXTER gasp]
[BAXTER grunts, gasps]
[BAXTER whimpers]
Wait just one moment!
Yes, my lord,
we recognise a pound
of flesh may be removed--
that's not in question.
But these aren't the terms!
The contract clearly
states one pound of flesh.
Meaning at any point
during its removal,
the shedding of a single
drop of blood is unacceptable!
Correct?
[JUDGE 18A]
Hm...
Sustained then.
Contractually, the plaintiff may
not spill the defendant's blood
during the act of repayment.
No bleeding?
Somehow, I must
cut into his flesh
without spilling a single drop.
Impossible.
[BAXTER]
I've won!
Foolish street urchin!
The moment you put your
name on that contract,
your fate was sealed.
My path to victory was assured!
I also have legal proof
you willingly forfeited
those 600 pounds to me.
None of your demands,
not a single one,
will be ever be met.
There's no possible
way you'll succeed.
[WILLIAM]
Well,
I wish to continue my
line of inquiry then.
[LAWYER 18A grunts]
[WILLIAM]
As the plaintiff,
may I call a witness
into the courtroom?
[BAXTER] Who is this
bloke? Do I know him?
[WILLIAM] I would like to
first question the defendant.
Mister Baxter,
you enjoy ordering steak
at restaurants, do you not?
That's right, I do.
Then if I may stand in
as the waiter,
place your order as you
normally would, please.
[BAXTER grunts]
I would like you to grill
me a half-pound of beef.
Is that sufficient?
Yes, thank you very much.
Moving along, I'd like
to question Mister Bremner.
[BREMNER]
Oh. Right.
[WILLIAM] You are a
waiter at the restaurant
Mister Baxter frequents,
are you not?
[BREMNER]
Yes, I am.
[BAXTER]
So that's who he is.
[WILLIAM] And Mister Baxter--
do you wait on him often?
[BREMNER]
Yes. He came in just yesterday.
I see. And did he
by chance order a steak?
[BAXTER]
What's he playing at?
Is the urchin implying
since I order steak often,
I must have money?
What a laughable argument.
Yes, and he seemed
to relish the taste
as he always does.
If I have this right,
Mister Baxter always orders
his favorite size and cut
and has no issue paying
for it. Is that correct?
Uh. Well, yes. That's correct.
[WILLIAM]
Well, then,
whenever Mister Baxter
orders his steak,
has he at any point asked
when you serve the half pound
for the blood to be
removed from the weight?
[BAXTER gasps]
[BREMNER]
The weight of the blood?
No, and I've been
a server for 20 years.
No one's ever made
that request before.
I trust I've made my point.
[BAXTER]
No, you haven't!
This whole argument is--
[WILLIAM]
I see you're confused.
We're establishing
your concept of "flesh."
[LAWYER 18A grunts]
[WILLIAM]
Earlier in court,
your lawyer argued
per our contract,
at no point could blood be added
to the pound of flesh removed.
Not one drop.
However, when the plaintiff
is a customer placing
his regular order of steak,
his logic differs.
For Mister Baxter,
the concept of meat includes all
the blood contained within.
You're wrong! I don't--
[WILLIAM]
If I am wrong,
then you would have asked
to remove the weight of
the blood whenever you ordered
your traditional half pound.
But as we know,
you didn't--not on any occasion.
In other words, it's been
conclusively demonstrated
when you signed the contract,
you understood a pound of flesh
included the
weight of the blood.
I'll collect your debt now.
[BAXTER] Enough!
This is-- It's chicanery!
[WILLIAM] I believe
you're doing the chicaning.
Your own solicitor said
the contract is valid
and a pound of flesh
may be cut out.
[WILLIAM]
Right, my Lord?
The lad is correct.
This is absurd!
The ignorant waif doesn't
even know the play on which
the terms of the
contract are based!
[WILLIAM]
"O, Antonio.
If thou art prepared to accept
Shylock's knife into thy bosom,
then lay bare thy breast!"
When it comes to Shakespeare,
I can recite every line from
all 40 of his works from memory.
But that's not possible.
You're a mere guttersnipe.
How're you...?
[WILLIAM]
Very well.
Now that the matter regarding
blood has been settled...
...it's time to claim
what's rightfully mine
and take my pound of flesh.
No one else needs to see this.
[BAXTER whimpering]
Wait.
Listen to reason!
N-No. No!
Wait.
[BAXTER whimpers]
[BAXTER]
Please, wait!
I said-- I said
wait just a second!
[BAXTER]
I swear, it's a lie! All of it!
The truth is the
title on my house,
I transferred it to a friend.
Same for the company!
I actually own all of it!
[BAXTER whimpers]
Say, what would you say to half?
Fifty percent of
everything I own!
My property, you name it!
[WILLIAM]
Just half?
[BAXTER whimpers]
That won't do.
I want all of your
worldly possessions.
Then we'll have a deal.
[BAXTER cries]
[BAXTER]
I... agree.
[MILVERTON] Following
the conclusion of the trial,
the young men donated
the vast wealth
they obtained from
Baxter to the orphanage,
and then disappeared.
Upon investigating
the adopted third son
who perished in that fire,
I arrived at this court record.
I have zero doubts.
The middle brother and the boy
from the trial are the same,
William James Moriarty.
After the family
manor burned down,
he took the place
of the real William.
And judging by the fact
that the other brothers
readily accepted him,
one can presume that all
of the brothers are complicit.
William James Moriarty.
[MILVERTON chuckles]
I see.
The name of my enemy.
[FRED]
I come bringing news.
I went by the courthouse.
It seems someone has taken
the records you wanted
to be discovered.
[FRED]
The man responsible
is a one Charles
Augustus Milverton.
It appears that his objective
was not to find precedent,
but to investigate
William's past.
Lord Milverton, you say?
The man owns several newspapers
and advertising firms.
He has even been nicknamed
the King of Media.
An aristocrat, no.
But nonetheless,
a prominent businessman.
What is this court
record you mentioned?
Well, back when Will was a kid,
he took this nobleman welsher
to court and won the case.
Why would you leave
such a thing to be found?
[BONDE gasps]
Then he must know.
[WILLIAM]
Everyone, listen here.
It's become quite evident
that Lord Milverton
has chosen to target me.
All of you should exercise
caution regarding him.
[WILLIAM]
Until further notice,
you are to consider
him our primary foe.
Eliminate him.
[HOLMES] Next time on
Moriarty the Patriot  :
"The White Knight
of London, Act One."